First World Flight
Marist College
First World Flight
1789 1984
Marist Archives and Special Collections 3399 North Road, Poughkeepsie, New York 12601
Lowell Thomas
2.1.1.2.11
1203 Linear feet
Items in this collection do not circulate and may be used in-house only.
Glass plate negatives
- Lowell Thomas Papers
  - Graphic Materials, 2
    - Photographs, 2.1
      - Glass plate negatives, 2.1.1
        - Lowell Thomas, 2.1.1.2
          - First World Flight, 2.1.1.2.11
              - John Harding, Jr., Lowell H. Smith, Henry Ogden, Leslie P. Arnold, Erik H. Nelson, Leigh Wade [from left to right], 1924; 56 (Box 1329)
                4x5
                film
              - Leigh Wade with his mascots, Jiggs and Maggie, 1924; 57
              - World Fliers in front of airplane, 1924; 58
              - Lowell Thomas surrounded by six world fliers in uniform, 1924; 59
                5x7
              - The young lady whose picture on celluloid flew round the world on the instrument-board of the New Orleans, 1924; 60
              - Eskimos in their kayaks alongside an iceberg, gazing at the first airplanes to ever visit Greenland, 1924; 61
              - The world cruiser Chicago and New Orleans in the iceberg infested harbor of Fredericksdal in Greenland, 1924; 62
              - A checkerboard of flooded rice-fields from the cockpit of an American world cruiser flying over China, 1924; 63
              - Captain Lowell H. Smith and Lieutenant Leslie P. Arnold in the world cruiser Chicago and Lieutenants Leigh Wade and Henry Ogden in the Boston winging their way past snowcapped Mount Shasta, 1924; 64
              - Cruiser with broken engine being trundled into a British hanger by a squad of British soldiers, 1924; 65
              - World cruisers over the palm fringed coast of Siam, 1924; 66
              - American world fliers passing over a Chinese junk at the mouth of the Yangtze River near Shanghai on man’s first flight across the Yellow Sea from Japan to China, 1924; 67
              - First aerial crossing of the Pacific[?] on man’s first flight around the world, 1924; 68
              - World cruisers over boat, 1924; 69
              - World cruisers flying over elephants in field, 1924; 70
              - World cruisers flying over elaborate harbor city on hill, 1924; 71
              - World cruisers flying over elaborate building, 1924; 72
              - World cruisers flying over tall building, majority of which is behind trees, 1924; 73
                4.5x6.5
              - Two airplanes flying over clouds, taken from airplane flying above, 1924; 74
              - Boats along coast, land covered in trees, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 75
              - Mountain along water, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 76
              - Mountain and lake, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 77
              - Airplane flying in valley, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 78
              - Boat in water, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 79
              - Land in distance, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 80
              - Icebergs in water, 1924; 81
              - Airplane flying over water, town and fields in background, 1924; 82
              - Two airplanes flying, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 83
              - Two airplanes flying, mountain in background, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 84
              - Small boats rowing toward airplane on water, 1924; 85
              - Two airplanes flying near mountains in distance, 1924; 86
              - Machine[?] in water, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 87
              - Airplane flying over town, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 88
              - Airplane flying in distance over town, photograph taken from airplane, 1924; 89
              - Two children, two men looking at camera, 1924; 90
              - Airplane on water, trees in background, 1924; 91